## Milton Mauricio Mora Salamanca

Email <u>milton9947@hotmail.com</u> Mobile (+57) 3176552954



#### About

Computer and system engineer, software engineering specialist, with 12 years of experience in IT areas, with focus in software development and architecture on different languages and platforms, oriented to maintain a vanguard knowledge with enthusiasm to the constantly upgrading and learning for the new technologies of the current industry.

Technical leading and participation on software development projects on agile frameworks ad methodologies for the enterprise environments, knowledge in programming languages backend and frontend, especially in OOP and AOP, microservices architectures and OCluod - OnPremise infrastructures, SQL - NoSQL tools and Database engines.

#### Experience

## Senior Software Engineer

Mill5 Colombia Bogotá DC - Remote Agosto 2022 - November 2022 Perform microservices development and extensibility, backend components development, solutions design for deployment web services to retail platforms, analysis and resolution of issues and bugs.

The following technologies and tools were used in the projects:

- Java (EE, SE8 15)
- Spring Boot Framework, RESTFul Webservices
- GraphQL
- Buildkite, Jenkins.
- · Git, Github, Git bash
- Apache Maven, Gradle
- DGS Framework
- Junit, Mockito
- Kotlin

## **Software Engineer**

EPAM Systems Colombia Bogotá DC - Remote August 2021 - August 2022 Perform microservices development and extensibility, backend components development and maintaining of frontend components, solutions design for deploy of software tools to the tourism and pharmaceutical sector, analysis and resolution of issues and bugs.

The following technologies and tools were used in the projects:

- Java (EE, SE8 15)
- Spring Boot Java Framework, RESTFul Webservices,
- DevOps CI/CD
- Docker, Kubernetes
- AWS S3, EC2, AWS-CLI, DynamoDB, SQS.
- Git, Gitlab, Git bash

- Apache Maven, Gradle
- Snowflake DB
- RabbitMQ

Technical Leader

Cognicase Management Consulting Bogotá DC April 2021 - August 2021 Perform microservices development and extensibility, backend components development and maintaining of frontend components, solutions design for deploy of software tools and integration of data with partners and financial products, analysis and resolution of issues and bugs.

The following technologies and tools were used in the projects:

- Java (EE, SE8 15)
- Spring Boot Java Framework, RESTFul Webservices, Swagger API
- Jenkins DevOps CI/CD DevSecOps
- Red Hat Openshift Container Platform
- Docker, Kubernetes
- AWS S3, Kinesis, Athena, EC2, AWS-CLI
- Git, Bitbucket, SourceTree
- Apache Maven, Artifactory
- Angular 8, Javascript, Typescript
- MongoDB, PostgreSQL

## Senior Developer

Grupo Cinte Colombia Bogotá DC October 2019 - April 2021 Microservices development, frontend components development, automation of data integration processes for analytics and statistics

The following technologies and tools were used in the projects:

- Java (EE, SE8 12)
- Spring Boot Java Framework, RESTFul Webservices, Swagger API
- Jenkins DevOps CI/CD DevSecOps
- Red Hat Openshift Container Platform
- Docker, Kubernetes
- AWS S3, Kinesis, Athena, EC2, AWS-CLI
- Git, Bitbucket, SourceTree
- Apache Maven, Artifactory
- Angular 8, Javascript, Typescript
- MongoDB, PostgreSQL

## Senior software Engineer

Capgemini SAS Bogotá DC January/2019 - October/2019 Microservices development, client webservices development, frontend applications development, backend and database development.

The following technologies and tools were used in the projects:

- Java (EE, SE7-8).
- Frameworks Backend (Spring MVC, Spring Boot, JPA, Hibernate)
- Frameworks FrontEnd (JSF-Primefaces, JQuery)
- SOAP Webservices, JAX-WS, Axis2
- RESTful Webservices Spring Boot
- PL/SQL Developer, Oracle SQL Developer.
- Gitlab, Maven, Artifactory, Jenkins.
- Apache Tomcat, JDBC Realms.
- CVS Tortoise

## **Development Analyst**

La Equidad Seguros OC Bogotá DC March/2016 - January/2019 • SOAPUI, Postman

Webservices development, client webservices development, frontend applications development, backend and database development.

The following technologies and tools were used in the projects:

- Java (EE, SE 7-8).
- Frameworks Java (JSF, Primefaces, Spring MVC, Hibernate, JPA, EJB, JAXWS,
- Axis2, Apache CXF).
- Otros Framework (JQUERY, HTML5, PL/SQL).
- PL/SQL Developer.
- SOAPUI, Postman.
- Github.
- Maven
- Oracle SQL Developer.
- IBM Websphere Aplication Server.
- Apache Tomcat, Glassfish server.
- SQL SERVER 2016 R2.

## Consultant IT - Solutions Analyst

Everis Colombia SA Bogotá DC October/2013 - march/2016 Webservices development, client webservices development, SOA BPM process development.

The following technologies and tools were used in the projects:

- WebMethods Software AG Designer 8
- Java (EE, SE, JSF).
- SOAPUI 4 (Herramienta de consumo de Servicios Web).
- IBM FileNet P8 (CE, PE, Record Manager, Workplace XT).
- SVN
- Oracle SQL Developer (Para consultas en BD).
- Java (Eclipse, JPA, JQUERY, EJBs).
- IBM FileNet P8 (CE, PE, Record Manager, Workplace XT).
- IBM Websphere Aplication Server 7.
- SQL SERVER 2008 R2.

# Applications and Database Developer

Agencia Logística de las Fuerzas Militares Bogotá DC Sept./2009 - october-2013 Web applications development and support, relational database development and administration.

The following technologies and tools were used in the projects:

- Java (EE, SE, JSP, JSF).
- PHP
- Oracle 9g
- SQL Server 2008 R2
- MySQL server
- PostgreSQL
- Apache Tomcat, Xampp

#### Education

## Software engineering specialist

Universidad Antonio Nariño Bogotá DC Postgraduate oriented to software development and architecture.

2019

## Computer engineer

Politécnico Grancolombiano Bogotá DC 2015

#### College degree

### Informatic technical

Corporación Universitaria Minuto

Technical degree in software development

#### **Projects**

de Dios Bogotá DC 2010

- https://www.midatacredito.com/
- https://servicios.laequidadseguros.coop/Intermediarios/
- https://servicios.laequidadseguros.coop/Cotizadores/
- https://servicios.laequidadseguros.coop/clientes/
- https://servicios.laequidadseguros.coop/portal/
- https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ionicframework.appclientes588268&hl=es\_CO

#### Certificates

ITIL Foundation V3 People cert April 2017 - May 2017

Master completo en JAVA de cero a experto Udemy May 2021

#### Skills:

- Operation analysis
- Computing analysis
- Self-learning
- Self-training
- Team working
- Comprehension and manage of change
- Interpersonal skills
- Goal oriented
- Leadership

#### Languages

Spanish (Native)

English

Middle level 60%

Milton Mauricio Mora Salamanca

Computer and system engineer

Contact: Mobile (+57) 317 655 2954